Phone: (+44) 07910-390 599 Webpage: http://www.hentula.com Email: joakim.hentula@gmail.com

Joakim Hentula 4 Hitchman Mews CV31 3QW Leamington Spa, Warwickshire United Kingdom

Curriculum Vitae - Joakim Hentula

Objective

Creating great games, working with talented people.

Profile

A programmer with eight years of professional games development experience. Disciplined, hard working and with a knack for problem solving. Does not back down from a challenge and is able to learn, understand and apply new technologies in a well organized and efficient manner.

A naturally supportive team-player who has been told he's a great teacher. Positive, creative, listens well and most of all eager to work with and learn from talented people making great games.

Expertise

- C++ (10+ years)
- Python
- C#
- Audio programming (in-house and AudioKinetic Wwise)
- Tools development (in house real time object editor, audio pipeline/)
- Multi platform development (Xbox 360, PS3, Steam, TRC/TCR compatibility)
- Perforce
- Has experience in various audio (Ableton Live, Cubase) and visual suites (Blender3D,
 3DS Max/MAXScript)

Professional experience

- 2015-Present, Codemasters, Audio programmer Dirt Rally Rewrote early audio reflections system. Vehicle audio.
- 2014-2015, Codemasters, Unity programmer Undisclosed Joined prototype team as sole programmer working on two game ideas based around user generated content and AI using Behaviour Trees.
- 2012-2014, Codemasters, Audio programmer GRID Autosport Revamped audio damage systems, audio system optimisations, implemented hot

Phone: (+44) 07910-390 599 Webpage: http://www.hentula.com Email: joakim.hentula@gmail.com

Joakim Hentula 4 Hitchman Mews CV31 3QW Leamington Spa, Warwickshire United Kingdom

reload solution for audio data.

- 2011-2012, Codemasters, Audio programmer GRID 2 Created audio mark up tool with real time in game editing, assisted in integrating 3rd party audio middleware.
- 2010-2011, Codemasters, Audio programmer DiRT: Showdown Joined audio programming team as sole audio programmer for the game, using in house audio solution.
- 2009 2010, Codemasters, Game programmer DiRT3

 Created a data driven component based game system with support for replay and network serialisation. Prototyped and developed USP Gymkhana game mode.
- 2008 2009, Codemasters, Game programmer Colin McRae: DiRT2 Created the career progression system, several game modes and a framework enabling game code to support both local and networked play.
- 2007 2008, Codemasters, Game programmer RaceDriver: GRID Created ghost-lap recording/playback system and PC installer, refactored save systems, integrated Games For Windows..

Achievements

Created component based game object system supporting replay and network serialisation. The system has subsequently been used by multiple teams on multiple projects.

Education

2004 - 2007, University of Skövde - Computer Game Development - Programming (Degree of Bachelor of Science with a major in Computer Science)

Languages

Swedish (native), English (fluent)

References

References will be supplied on request.

Example of previous projects

Please visit http://www.hentula.com for example projects.